We're way less efficient as a duo.
Damn it!
I thought Heal Mushrooms
were basically a guaranteed drop,
but we killed four Matango
and didn't see a single one.
Maybe Ruche's Lady Luck
was doing something after all.
It didn't seem like anyone else
was going after Matangos.
It was just a coincidence.
She could've stayed
if she hadn't demanded a cut
from selling the Blood-soaked Sword.
Should we invite her back?
Listen, Reiss.
I have my dignity to preserve.
I can't invite her back
after everything I said.
I'd rather die than ask her for anything.
Fortunately, we've got plenty of
money from selling that sword.
There's no need to panic.
We can take our time finding someone
who gets it, even if they're low-level.
That dungeon? Not a rank D or C one?
Where is he? I don't see anything.
What's going on?
Maybe someone defeated
a high-level monster.
Him again?
Aren't Patchwork Bears strong?
I've seen him before.
A fresh rank E and rank F?
They beat the Angel's Playbox?
The recommended level is 50!
You're kidding, right?
Th-They did what?!
Loading
Begin Adventure
Episode 10\h\h\h\h\hNegotiation
We weren't trying to beat the dungeon.
The Dreamlord attacked us
while it was Wandering.
If you don't believe me,
two other adventurers were involved.
You can ask them.
Very well.
The city was offering a bounty
for defeating the Angel's Playbox,
so I'll confirm with them.
Bounties are sometimes placed on
dungeons near cities and villages.
Monsters tend to come out of dungeons
that have been left alone for too long,
and they can lead to
disasters in the area.
A dungeon's recommended level depends
on the region in which it appears,
with a clear separation between
low and high-level areas.
Some believe it's caused by
the mana flowing in the region,
while others say it's the will ofAlxeros
and beyond human comprehension,
but nothing is known for certain.
High-level adventurers tend to operate out
of cities where dangerous dungeons appear.
The pay is better, and it does
more to serve the kingdom.
Because of that, no one in Rondalm
could beat the Angel's Playbox.
Fearing the dungeon would be ignored,
the mayor put a bounty on it.
A bounty, huh?
I wasn't expecting one
and didn't even look into it.
How much is it?
Ten million gold.
Ten million?!
Ten million gold, huh?
We really appreciate that.
I know I should be glad, but our drops
have ruined my ability to react normally.
Was it Lady Luck?
Did they get a rare drop from
a recommended level 50 Dreamlord?
That Elymas guy scouted Ruche
as soon as he figured she had Lady Luck.
I didn't think your Lady Luck
would apply to this, too.
Then they suddenly got a huge payday.
They seem completely
indifferent to 10,000,000 gold.
Just how much money have they made?
I'm just lucky all the time.
Also, you'll be promoted to rank D
in accordance with guild regulations.
You'll be jumping
from rank F to D, Ms. Ruche.
Rank B
Rank C
Rank D
Rank E
Rank F
Rank A
Rank S
R-Ruche is rank D?
It's not clear how, but she rose
beyond our reach at some point.
Ruche is rank D? Rank D? Ruche?
Cline?
What's gotten into you?!
We did—
Ruche!
I'm sorry!
I've mended my ways!
Please come back!
We can split the money from selling
the Blood-soaked Sword evenly, okay?
Pathetic.
Let's go, Ruche.
It'll take time to investigate.
Okay.
W-Wait! At least hear me out!
Could you...
Could you at least...
Yikes.
This place looks expensive.
I'm excited.
Thank you for waiting, sir.
The promotions and bounty
were happy accidents.
Our promotions to rank D
raised our skill point cap to 45.
The Fang of Smoldering Insanity
skillbook is within reach, too.
How should we farm money next?
Wh-What is it, Mr. Elymas?
Oh, sorry.
We're celebrating.
I should focus on having fun.
That's right.
Let's have a fun time.
Cheers!
We said we'd order
whatever we wanted today.
I've always dreamed of having all I can
eat at the Alchemist King's Stove.
Alchemist
King's
Stove
Once I felt like I'd made it
as an adventurer,
I wanted to come here with my party.
I thought I'd be here with
Mr. Cline and Ms. Reiss, though.
Did you forget that I paid you
the bare minimum? Ungrateful!
You most certainly did not!
King Crab and Black Truffle Sauce Pie
Their king crab and black truffle
sauce pie costs 8,000 gold?!
I didn't think it'd be this expensive.
I nearly ordered one.
Mr. Elymas, don't order
anything from this page!
Let's look for something under 4,000 gold!
One king crab and black truffle
sauce pie, please.
What?!
Yes, sir.
A-Are you sure?
It must not have sunk in yet.
Here's your king crab
and black truffle sauce pie.
It's really good.
I'm in heaven.
This is good, too.
I'm glad to hear that.
We should discuss how to split
the loot and gold we earned.
First, do you want to use
the skillbook, Ruche?
I think it'd be worthwhile for you
to have Intermediate Wind Magic.
You're not going to use it?
No.
It's not bad, but I'd like to aim higher.
I've already got a build in mind.
Then I won't use it either.
What? Are you sure?
With this skill tree, you'll have
an easy time finding a party for a while.
But that would mean
having different goals.
I want to aim higher, too.
Besides, it'd be sad
to say goodbye so soon.
Then we'll sell it.
To be honest, that'll help a lot.
Were you short on money?
After subtracting various expenses,
we earned about 57,000,000 gold.
Just hearing the amount makes me dizzy.
We'll split this 80/20,
so you get 46,000,000 gold.
46,000,000G
What?!
And I get 11,000,000 gold.
Ruche: 46,000,000G
Elymas: 11,000,000G
Please! You won't regret it!
Let's form a party!
How about an 80/20 split?
You'd get 80%, of course.
I'm fine with 20%.
That offer was still on the table?!
What's going on?
Ruche, everyone's looking at us.
Are they fighting?
Is 80/20 not good enough?
No, I'm sorr—no, wait!
There's no way I could
ever accept that amount.
Where did that 80/20 split come from?
Most deals involve a split like that.
In what universe?!
You can't seriously expect me
to accept 40,000,000 gold!
I already can't thank you enough
for raising my level this much!
Ruche!
I thought it was a fair split...
It's called a Lucky Bird.
We still haven't agreed on
how to split the treasure.
We decided to visit the Hall of
Broken Grimoires to sell our items.
Well, well. You're back.
With a sweet girl this time.
Friend of yours?
You'd better still have it.
You don't trust me, do you?
Of course I've still got
the Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
I value my customers' trust.
This shop has the item you want?
She seems like a sweet girl.
You're not planning to make her
use that skillbook, are you?
Don't be ridiculous.
I would never do that.
It's for me.
Uh-huh. Either way,
you're a freak if you want that.
I came to have you appraise some items.
Oh, really? You seem too smart
to consider selling anything here.
Well, this is a surprise.
Two Dazzling Raana Decorative Blades.
If I'd known you were such a big shot,
I would've treated you like one.
My mistake.
I'm not interested
in tedious negotiations.
I'll sell them to you for 30,000,000 gold.
Any less, and I'll take them
somewhere else.
You'll have a hard time getting
30,000,000 gold at a legitimate shop.
But here, no rumors will spread, and you
won't have to worry about jealousy.
You shouldn't take unnecessary
risks for a little extra money.
I'll give you 25,000,000 gold.
Th-This old woman...
I said I didn't want to negotiate.
Mr. Elymas, she's not wrong.
Twenty-five million gold
is a lot of money.
Don't be swayed, Ruche.
She'll take advantage
of any weakness we show.
Thirty million gold is a high price, and
it'll be tough to get that anywhere else.
Considering the risk,
I could just sell them here.
But if I let her control the conversation,
she'll negotiate for even less.
I have gold from selling Magic Stones.
I can hold onto the swords
until I can get a good deal.
Then I can't make you
do anything. That's a shame.
But that's not why
you're really here, is it?
I have a skillbook
dropped by a Dreamlord.
I'm thinking about using it,
but if you'll give me a good price,
I'll consider selling it.
A skillbook?
I can't believe you found one so quickly.
You—no, the two of you might be
known as heroes before long.
I see. So you want to sell this here.
She's interested,
but how much can I get her to pay?
The market price is 20,000,000 gold.
I'd be taking a risk
by buying this from you.
The guild would only give you
7,000,000 gold for it.
You seem skilled, so I'll bump up the
price since we might do business again.
I'll buy it for 14,000,000 gold.
And you'll put it up for sale
at an absurd markup, right?
It's easy to find a buyer
for Intermediate Wind Magic.
If you want to be friends, then I think
you could give me 22,000,000 gold for it.
Hot!
You brat!
You have no intention of using it, do you?
Don't be so brazenly greedy!
Who's the greedy one?!
I'm offering to be a customer!
You don't have to be so stingy!
Panic
Um...
Um, so...
Mr. Elymas, how much is that Fang of
Smoldering Insanity skillbook you want?
What now, girl?
You're interrupting our fun.
The rare skillbook he wants
costs 55,000,000 gold.
The market price is only
30,000,000 gold, though.
She's definitely taking advantage.
Fifty-five million gold...
I thought I knew what to expect,
but that's still so expensive.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I have an idea.
Would you trade that skillbook and these
items for the Fang of Smoldering Insanity?
What? That's hardly a fair deal.
That's what you interrupted us for?
No, wait.
Getting rid of a skillbook no one wants
for items that are easy to sell isn't bad.
Ruche's deal is good for us, too.
We'd keep the payout from
the Magic Stones and slaying monsters,
plus the Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
Girl.
You shouldn't interrupt
a merchant's business,
but betting on a future hero
isn't a bad idea.
I accept those terms.
You do?
No, wait! Then you
won't get your full share!
It's fine.
Think of it as a thank you
present from me.
Th-This is too much for a thank you.
And we don't know
if next time will go as well.
What if we have to disband
our party for some reason?
Mr. Elymas.
Are you planning to abandon me?
I'm starting to think you're
preparing for a clean break.
I-I'm not, but just in case...
Then there's no problem.
Come on, ma'am. Let's trade
before Elymas can say anything else.
Good job convincing him.
Hold on tight so he doesn't get away.
What?!
Why are they getting along?
Somewhere within the County of Edvaughn
How revolting.
Lady Malice, that's enough!
Lifeforce Transfer has ended!
Her methods seem a bit savage.
It's good EXP, but still...
Right?
You may have been exiled,
but you don't go down easily.
I've known that since we were young.
I need to take my time with you.
Isn't that right,
my dear Elymas?
Translator:
Sho Stifler
Timer:
Krzysztof Kunc
Editor:
Salem Alabanza
Quality Control:
Gabriella Alabanza
Final Quality Control:
Sriram Gurunathan
The Fang of Smoldering Insanity
skillbook is finally mine!
"Beware of those with this Skill Tree.
Dragging his shattered body
and letting his torn tail flutter,
not even the God of Death dares
approach his unstoppable rampage!"
I've missed this
unsettling descriptive text.
Next time, "Inescapable Past."
No, wait. I need to stay grounded.